<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Red Bay</title>
    <link>https://theredbay.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Red Bay</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://theredbay.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GMorse Part 1 - Project Layout</title>
      <link>https://theredbay.net/projects/gmorse/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://theredbay.net/projects/gmorse/part1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you made here, I&amp;rsquo;m assuming you&amp;rsquo;re at least intrigued about what it takes to implement a Morse code decoder. This is&#xA;going to be a multi-part article. In this first part I&amp;rsquo;ll be laying down the foundation of the project, identifying what&#xA;makes up a functional decoder, and break down the project into different steps.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-morse-code&#34;&gt;Introduction to Morse code&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So what &lt;em&gt;IS&lt;/em&gt; Morse code? You&amp;rsquo;ve probably at least heard the term before or maybe actually heard some in an old movie or&#xA;on Youtube. Morse code was invented by Samuel Morse in the first part of the 19th century when he co-developed an&#xA;electric telegraph system with Josepth Henry and Alfred Vail. The &amp;ldquo;on&amp;rdquo;/&amp;ldquo;off&amp;rdquo; nature of the telegraph system&amp;rsquo;s electrical&#xA;signals made it obvious that establishing a code to transmit natural language over electric wire was necessary.&#xA;Essentially, Morse code encodes all the letters of the alphabet (and some symbols) into sequences of short and long&#xA;electrical pulses, seperated by varying lengths of silences. Conventionally, short pulses are referred to as &amp;ldquo;dits&amp;rdquo;&#xA;while long pulses are referred to as &amp;ldquo;dahs&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Previse</title>
      <link>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/htb-previse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/htb-previse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hey all, as promised, I can now spend more time doing some HackTheBox machines since my CISSP&#xA;studies are behind me and certification is done. Haven&amp;rsquo;t done any in a while so let&amp;rsquo;s kick it off&#xA;with an easy one.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theredbay.net/img/htb-previse/infocard.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a  Linux based machine, easy, and going to be retired in a few weeks. It&amp;rsquo;s also &lt;code&gt;m4lwhere&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;first machine so this might be fresh and interesting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Journey to CISSP</title>
      <link>https://theredbay.net/infosec/cissp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://theredbay.net/infosec/cissp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, it&amp;rsquo;s finally done. Over the holiday period in 2020, I vowed that 2021 would be the year where&#xA;I solidified my credentials in cyber security. Move from a passive &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m interested in security&amp;rdquo; to&#xA;walking the walk. The main objective is to eventually make a move into a cyber security centered&#xA;role. I think there are multiple ways of achieving this and they all require different levels of&#xA;efforts. This blog is one of them. I learned so much from reading articles and attending security&#xA;conferences over the past few years. Writing walkthoughs for challenges and HackTheBox machines&#xA;are a way for me to give back on the knowledge sharing front. It also serves as a reminder on how&#xA;I solved them too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spectra</title>
      <link>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/htb-spectra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/htb-spectra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hello all, here&amp;rsquo;s an other one for your entertainment purposes! Today, we will be looking at&#xA;&lt;code&gt;spectra&lt;/code&gt; &amp;ndash; A bit late since this box was solved back in May of 2021 but I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to the&#xA;walkthrough part until now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theredbay.net/img/htb-spectra/infocard.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The information card states that this is an easy machine and was released at the beginning of the&#xA;year. One difference from others that we&amp;rsquo;ve looked at up until now is that the OS states &lt;strong&gt;Other&lt;/strong&gt;.&#xA;This just means that it&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily a Linux box so we&amp;rsquo;ll keep that in mind while we look&#xA;around. To break this box, we will also be going over a couple of new tools. We will be looking at&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OJ/gobuster&#34;&gt;Gobuster&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.metasploit.com&#34;&gt;Metasploit&lt;/a&gt; so do take&#xA;the time to either install &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kali.org/&#34;&gt;Kali Linux&lt;/a&gt; and have the tools ready to go or&#xA;install them on your machine before proceeding &amp;ndash; installing and configuring them is out of scope&#xA;for this article.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delivery</title>
      <link>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/htb-delivery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/htb-delivery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hello all and welcome to my write-up for the &lt;code&gt;delivery&lt;/code&gt; HackTheBox machine. For those looking for a&#xA;quick step-by-step guide, please skip to the &lt;a href=&#34;#tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/a&gt; section at the end.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theredbay.net/img/htb-delivery/infocard.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;delivery&lt;/code&gt; is an easy machine, even by HackTheBox standards. There isn&amp;rsquo;t much more to it than&#xA;reading and poking around but it still teaches us some basics enumeration, configuration and&#xA;some password cracking with &lt;code&gt;hashcat&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First things first. Let&amp;rsquo;s add the &lt;code&gt;delivery.htb&lt;/code&gt; entry to our hosts file, point that to&#xA;&lt;code&gt;10.10.10.222&lt;/code&gt;, and get to work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing ROCm-OpenCL runtime on Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://theredbay.net/misc/rocm-opencl-runtime-hashcat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://theredbay.net/misc/rocm-opencl-runtime-hashcat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Greetings folks, this is going to be a short but usefull one. For those in a hurry, skip to the&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;./#installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/a&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start by setting context. What are we trying to solve here? We&amp;rsquo;re here because we want to&#xA;&amp;ldquo;recover&amp;rdquo; some passwords using &lt;code&gt;hashcat&lt;/code&gt;. We have been through the excellent Arch Linux Wiki&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Hashcat&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; for installing &lt;code&gt;hashcat&lt;/code&gt;, got&#xA;everything installed, tried using it, and got an error that the currently installed OpenCL&#xA;driver is unstable and cannot be used.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doctor</title>
      <link>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/htb-doctor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:25:37 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/htb-doctor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Greetings, here is my write-up for the &lt;code&gt;doctor&lt;/code&gt; HackTheBox machine. I hope you enjoy the read! If&#xA;you&amp;rsquo;re in a hurry, skip to the &lt;a href=&#34;#tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/a&gt; section at the end.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://theredbay.net/img/htb-doctor/infocard.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Doctor is considered an easy Linux box by HackTheBox standards. It&amp;rsquo;s a well rounded box because&#xA;its solution is composed of a mix of basic enumeration, basic priviledge escalation and also some&#xA;recent CVE exploitation that can be accomplished with off-the-shelf tools. As we will see, the&#xA;hardest part in breaking &lt;code&gt;doctor&lt;/code&gt; is finding &lt;strong&gt;where&lt;/strong&gt; to exploit it and getting a foot hold on it.&#xA;A real head scratcher that reminds us that the solution is always right under our nose.  We&amp;rsquo;re&#xA;either overthinking it or simply not seeing it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
