<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Red Bay</title>
    <link>https://theredbay.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Red Bay</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Reda Baydoun</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theredbay.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spectra - HackTheBox Write-up</title>
      <link>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/htb-spectra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/htb-spectra/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hello all, here&amp;rsquo;s an other one for your entertainment purposes! Today, we will be looking at spectra &amp;ndash; A bit late since this box was solved back in May of 2021 but I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to the walkthrough part until now.
The information card states that this is an easy machine and was released at the beginning of the year. One difference from others that we&amp;rsquo;ve looked at up until now is that the OS states Other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delivery - HackTheBox Write-up</title>
      <link>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/htb-delivery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/htb-delivery/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hello all and welcome to my write-up for the delivery HackTheBox machine. For those looking for a quick step-by-step guide, please skip to the TL;DR section at the end.
delivery is an easy machine, even by HackTheBox standards. There isn&amp;rsquo;t much more to it than reading and poking around but it still teaches us some basics enumeration, configuration and some password cracking with hashcat.
First things first. Let&amp;rsquo;s add the delivery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing ROCm-OpenCL runtime on Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://theredbay.net/misc/rocm-opencl-runtime-hashcat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theredbay.net/misc/rocm-opencl-runtime-hashcat/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Greetings folks, this is going to be a short but usefull one. For those in a hurry, skip to the Installation section.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start by setting context. What are we trying to solve here? We&amp;rsquo;re here because we want to &amp;ldquo;recover&amp;rdquo; some passwords using hashcat. We have been through the excellent Arch Linux Wiki documentation for installing hashcat, got everything installed, tried using it, and got an error that the currently installed OpenCL driver is unstable and cannot be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctor - HackTheBox Write-up</title>
      <link>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/htb-doctor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:25:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/htb-doctor/</guid>
      <description>Intro Greetings, here is my write-up for the doctor HackTheBox machine. I hope you enjoy the read! If you&amp;rsquo;re in a hurry, skip to the TL;DR section at the end.
Doctor is considered an easy Linux box by HackTheBox standards. It&amp;rsquo;s a well rounded box because its solution is composed of a mix of basic enumeration, basic priviledge escalation and also some recent CVE exploitation that can be accomplished with off-the-shelf tools.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
