<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HackTheBox - Write-ups on The Red Bay</title>
    <link>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HackTheBox - Write-ups on The Red Bay</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Reda Baydoun</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Previse - HackTheBox Write-up</title>
      <link>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/htb-previse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/htb-previse/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hey all, as promised, I can now spend more time doing some HackTheBox machines since my CISSP studies are behind me and certification is done. Haven&amp;rsquo;t done any in a while so let&amp;rsquo;s kick it off with an easy one.
This is a Linux based machine, easy, and going to be retired in a few weeks. It&amp;rsquo;s also m4lwhere&amp;rsquo;s first machine so this might be fresh and interesting.
Before we dig in, this article won&amp;rsquo;t be as detailed as the others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectra - HackTheBox Write-up</title>
      <link>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/htb-spectra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/htb-spectra/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hello all, here&amp;rsquo;s an other one for your entertainment purposes! Today, we will be looking at spectra &amp;ndash; A bit late since this box was solved back in May of 2021 but I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to the walkthrough part until now.
The information card states that this is an easy machine and was released at the beginning of the year. One difference from others that we&amp;rsquo;ve looked at up until now is that the OS states Other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delivery - HackTheBox Write-up</title>
      <link>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/htb-delivery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/htb-delivery/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hello all and welcome to my write-up for the delivery HackTheBox machine. For those looking for a quick step-by-step guide, please skip to the TL;DR section at the end.
delivery is an easy machine, even by HackTheBox standards. There isn&amp;rsquo;t much more to it than reading and poking around but it still teaches us some basics enumeration, configuration and some password cracking with hashcat.
First things first. Let&amp;rsquo;s add the delivery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctor - HackTheBox Write-up</title>
      <link>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/htb-doctor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:25:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theredbay.net/infosec/htb/htb-doctor/</guid>
      <description>Intro Greetings, here is my write-up for the doctor HackTheBox machine. I hope you enjoy the read! If you&amp;rsquo;re in a hurry, skip to the TL;DR section at the end.
Doctor is considered an easy Linux box by HackTheBox standards. It&amp;rsquo;s a well rounded box because its solution is composed of a mix of basic enumeration, basic priviledge escalation and also some recent CVE exploitation that can be accomplished with off-the-shelf tools.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
